MARCUS OKODUGHA

Software Engineer <u>marcusokodugha.com</u> 🗹



Skills

- · Backend Development
- Frontend Development
- Native App Development
- · Agile, Scrum
- Networking
- · UI/UX
- Machine Learning
- Databases (SQL, NoSQL)
- Algorithms
- Data Structures
- DevOps

Development stack

- · Java, Spring Boot, Swing
- C Programming
- · HTML, CSS
- · JavaScript, TypeScript
- Angular
- React.js
- Vue.is
- · Android, Kotlin
- · C# .Net
- Node.js
- Python
- PHP
- · Git,GitHub
- · Assembler, Risc-V
- Figma
- Docker
- Kubernetes

Languages

- Swedish
- English

Contact

- MarcusOkodugha.com
- **4** +46 700150566
- Marcus.Okodugha247@gmail.com
- Linkedin Marcus Okodugha
- GitHub My Organisation
- GitHub Marcus Okodugha

About me

Software Engineer at Saab, working with full stack development, systems integration and AI product development in a high-security environment. Foundation in Java for backend and systems development, with experience across web, mobile, database and cloud technologies. I adapt quickly to different stacks, as shown on my portfolio page www.marcusokodugha.com which demonstrates applied results in AI, web and mobile solutions. Previously Product Owner at AFRY, where I led the development of a full stack Book and Claim system and coordinated an Agile team. My background also includes team-oriented training as a Jägarsoldat in the Swedish Army Ranger Battalion, and a degree in Software Engineering from KTH. I am the engineer you call when you need real value created.

Work Experience



Software Engineer, SAAB

2024 - Present

Specialized in Artificial intelligence, sensors, and data streams related to the product in a high-security environment at SAAB Järfälla. In a Scrum team of ten, I serve as an AI-specialized developer. development is mostly carried out in Java and C++.



Full-stack Developer, Flygresor.se

2024

Refresh of the last-minute travel page, optimized for performance, user-friendliness, conversion rates, and mobile responsiveness, accommodating over 300,000 monthly visitors.



Manager, MW Group Stockholm

2021 - 2023

Consulting assignments with various corporate clients. Key assignment: Security Manager at Stockholm Arlanda Airport.



Product Owner / Full-stack Developer, AFRY

2023

Product Owner at AFRY, I developed the frontend of a sustainability-focused Book and Claim system and led a team to meet the project's goals using Agile methodologies.



Ranger Soldier, Army Ranger Battalion (K4) Arvidsjaur

2019 - 2020

I specialized in precision marksmanship (AG g0) and long-range reconnaissance, supporting mission objectives, and completed basic medical training. These experiences enhanced my attention to detail, strategic planning, risk assessment, and ability to stay composed under pressure, making me effective at teamwork.



Salesperson, Förebygg Stockholm

2020

Sales of ID protection services B2C and B2B

Education



Computer science, KTH Royal Institute of Technology 2020 - 2024



Natural Science, Midsommarkransens Gymnasium 2016 - 2019

